we've been asked to write a program
that iterates over an array and builds a
new array that is the result
of incrementing each value in the
original array
by two so at the end of this program
we're going to have two arrays the
original array
and this new array and we want to output
both of them using p
so there's a few steps here let's just
begin by creating our original array
and we'll make this an array of integers
and i'll initialize an empty array we'll
call this new r
and this is where we'll collect our new
values
just to start out let's output both of
these arrays
and run our code to make sure we're
seeing what we expect
and we do we see our original array and
our new array which is currently empty
now we want to populate our new array
with five
elements and each element is going to be
an element from the original array
incremented by two
to do this we can iterate through the
original array
we can use the each method
and each element of this array will be
passed to the block as an argument
and we'll name that parameter n
now let's stop here and run our code
we're not going to put anything into our
new array yet we're simply going to
output the result
of adding 2 to each element
we'll run our code
and we can see five lines of output 3
4 5 6 and 7 and when we compare these
lines of
output to the elements in the original
array below
we see that these are the original
elements incremented by two
so this is what we want
now we need to add these to our new
array
we can use what is sometimes called the
shovel operator
this is an array method to append each
of these incremented values
into the new array
now after iterating through our original
array
and appending its elements incremented
by two
into our new array we expect to see the
final result that we want
and writing our code that's what we see